typeracer.com 2012-12-30

# TypeRacer Privacy Policy

## Website Visitors

Like most website operators, TypeRacer collects non-personally-identifying information of the sort that web browsers and servers typically make available, such as the browser type, language preference, referring site, and the date and time of each visitor request. TypeRacer's purpose in collecting non-personally identifying information is to better understand how TypeRacer's visitors use its website. From time to time, TypeRacer may release non-personally-identifying information in the aggregate, e.g., by publishing a report on trends in the usage of its website.

TypeRacer also collects potentially personally-identifying information like Internet Protocol (IP) addresses. TypeRacer does not use such information to identify its visitors, however, and does not disclose such information, other than under the same circumstances that it uses and discloses personally-identifying information, as described below.

## Gathering of Personally-Identifying Information

Certain visitors to TypeRacer's websites choose to interact with TypeRacer in ways that require TypeRacer to gather personally-identifying information. The amount and type of information that TypeRacer gathers depends on the nature of the interaction. For example, we ask visitors who sign up for an account at TypeRacer.com to provide a username, email address, and a date of birth (as a security measure for password retrieval). In each case, TypeRacer collects such information only insofar as is necessary or appropriate to fulfill the purpose of the visitor's interaction with TypeRacer. TypeRacer does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below. And visitors can always refuse to supply personally-identifying information, with the caveat that it may prevent them from engaging in certain website-related activities.

Notwithstanding anything else herein, we may partner with third party advertisers who may (themselves or through their partners) place or recognize a unique cookie on your browser. These cookies enable more customized ads, content or services to be provided to you. To trigger these cookies, we may pass an encrypted or "hashed" (non-human readable) identifier corresponding to your email address to a Web advertising partner, who may place a cookie on your computer. No personally identifiable information is on, or is connected to, these cookies. To opt-out of these cookies, please go to <http://www.privacychoice.org/choose>

## Aggregated Statistics

TypeRacer may collect statistics about the behavior of visitors to its websites. For instance, TypeRacer may gather information about the number of races a user has participated in. TypeRacer may display this information publicly or provide it to others. However, TypeRacer does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below.

* * *

The following sections contain a detailed privacy policy in accordance with [The World Wide Web Consortium (W3C)](http://www.w3.org/) recommendations.

## About Us

This is a privacy policy for TypeRacer. Our homepage on the Web is located at [ http://www.typeracer.com](http://www.typeracer.com/). The full text of our privacy policy is available on the Web at [ http://play.typeracer.com/privacy/privacy_policy.html](http://play.typeracer.com/privacy/privacy_policy.html) Users may go to [ ]() for information on how to opt-in or opt-out of use of their information. 

We invite you to contact us if you have questions about this policy. You may contact us by e-mail at [ contact@typeracer.com](mailto:contact@typeracer.com). 

## Dispute Resolution and Privacy Seals

We have the following privacy seals and/or dispute resolution mechanisms. If you think we have not followed our privacy policy in some way, they can help you resolve your concern. 

  * **Dispute Resolution** : Please contact customer support with your privacy concerns. 

## Additional Information

This policy is valid until 1 Jan, 2011 at 12:00:00 EST. 

## Data Collection

P3P policies declare the data they collect in groups (also referred to as "statements"). This policy contains 2 data groups. The data practices of each group will be explained separately. 

* * *

### Group "Basic information"

We collect the following information: 

  * Navigation and click-stream data
  * Computer information
  * Current location data

At the user's option, we may also collect the following data: 

  * Preference data
  * User's Name
  * Year
  * Month
  * User's Gender
  * Home e-mail address

This data will be used for the following purposes:

  * Completion and support of the current activity.
  * Web site and system administration.
  * Research and development.

This data will be used by ourselves and our agents. 

The following explanation is provided for why this data is collected:

> Data collected from all Web users: access logs, and search strings (if entered).

* * *

### Group "Cookies"

At the user's option, we will collect the following data: 

  * HTTP cookies

This data will be used for the following purposes:

  * Research and development.
  * One-time tailoring.

This data will be used by ourselves and our agents. 

The following explanation is provided for why this data is collected:

> Cookies are used to track visitors to our site, so we can better understand what portions of our site best serve you.

* * *

## Cookies

Cookies are a technology which can be used to provide you with tailored information from a Web site. A cookie is an element of data that a Web site can send to your browser, which may then store it on your system. You can set your browser to notify you when you receive a cookie, giving you the chance to decide whether to accept it. 

Our site makes use of cookies. Cookies are used for the following purposes: 

  * User targeting 
  * Research and development 

* * *

## Compact Policy Summary

The compact policy which corresponds to this policy is: 

        CP="CAO DSP COR CURa ADMa DEVa TAIa OUR BUS IND PHY ONL UNI COM NAV DEM PRE LOC"

The following table explains the meaning of each field in the compact policy. 

**Field**|  **Meaning**  
---|---  
`CP=` | This is the compact policy header; it indicates that what follows is a P3P compact policy.  
`CAO` |  Access is available to contact and other information.   
`DSP` |  The policy contains at least one dispute-resolution mechanism.   
`COR` |  Violations of this policy will be corrected.   
`CURa` |  The data is used for completion of the current activity.   
`ADMa` |  The data is used for site administration.   
`DEVa` |  The data is used for research and development.   
`TAIa` |  The data is used for tailoring the site.   
`OUR` |  The data is given to ourselves and our agents.   
`BUS` |  Our business practices specify how long the data will be kept.   
`IND` |  The data will be kept indefinitely.   
`PHY` |  Physical contact information is collected.   
`ONL` |  Online contact information is collected.   
`UNI` |  Unique identifiers are collected.   
`COM` |  Computer information is collected.   
`NAV` |  Navigation and clickstream data is collected.   
`DEM` |  Demographic and socioeconomic data is collected.   
`PRE` |  Preference information is collected.   
`LOC` |  Current location information is collected.   
  
The compact policy is sent by the Web server along with the cookies it describes. For more information, see the P3P deployment guide at <http://www.w3.org/TR/p3pdeployment>. 

* * *

## Policy Evaluation

Microsoft Internet Explorer 6 will evaluate this policy's compact policy whenever it is used with a cookie. The actions IE will take depend on what privacy level the user has selected in their browser (Low, Medium, Medium High, or High; the default is Medium. In addition, IE will examine whether the cookie's policy is considered satisfactory or unsatisfactory, whether the cookie is a session cookie or a persistent cookie, and whether the cookie is used in a first-party or third-party context. This section will attempt to evaluate this policy's compact policy against Microsoft's stated behavior for IE6. 

**Note:** this evaluation is currently experimental and should not be considered a substitute for testing with a real Web browser. 

**Satisfactory policy** : this compact policy is considered _satisfactory_ according to the rules defined by Internet Explorer 6. IE6 will accept cookies accompanied by this policy under the High, Medium High, Medium, Low, and Accept All Cookies settings.
